BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
[♪ opening theme song playing]
EPISODE 32: OTHER PEOPLE'S HOMES
[birds chirping]
♪
[Fern groans]
Mistress Frieren,
which do you think
would be better?
A dress is a dress, isn't it?
And before you run off today,
I need you to tie up my hair.
[Frieren grunts, groans]
[FRIEREN] This is torturous.
I can apologize,
if that's what it will take
to stop you from braiding
so vengefully.
♪
If you're so desperate
for my attention,
how about you and I
go on a date?
-[footsteps approaching]
-[Stark gasps softly]
You ready to go?
Yes.
♪
You're not wearing
your usual outfit today.
Why's that?
[FERN] Uh?
Because... this is a date.
[STARK] Mmm.
Fair enough.
♪
[WOMAN] I don't buy it!
-It's the truth!
-You're kidding!
[woman laughs]
♪
[STARK] Huh?
Has Fern been this cute
the entire time?
Well, you ready for some fun?
Mr. Stark, you seem
stiffer than normal.
Nope, no stiffness here.
[STARK] Hm?
Why did you stop?
Just tell me,
where are we going?
There's a marketplace up ahead
that I thought
we could check out.
A marketplace?
Where Mistress Frieren
has been shopping?
Yeah, because
we're in a bigger city,
she says there are loads
of rare magical items to find.
[Frieren chuckles]
Wow, how useful.
[FERN] That explains
the mountain of curiosities
piling up at the inn.
More?
Be careful not to get caught
in an avalanche.
The other day, I found her
passed out under the junk.
-[Frieren snores]
-[FERN] Uh?
[STARK] Take a passion too far
and it gets scary.
[FERN] It was.
Speaking of her passions,
I bet she's already back
at the hot springs.
I appreciate a good soak,
but she must be
tired of it by now.
I know I'd be.
If I were her,
I'd need to
change it up a little bit.
Today, she did. Because of me,
she's sporting a new hairstyle.
[Frieren sighs]
How divine.
Your usual updo is cute enough,
but those braids are precious!
♪
Whenever we're alone,
we end up talking about
Mistress Frieren.
Well, it's not like there's
much else to discuss.
[FEMALE SHOPKEEP] Take a look!
I'll give you a discount.
[STARK] Do you want
to get something to eat?
No, thank you. Not yet.
Okay, then.
♪
Pretty.
Apparently,
couples get a discount.
Guess dating's worth it
for the deals alone.
You're awfully blunt, Mr. Stark.
♪
This stuff doesn't look
particularly magical or rare.
These shops cater
to all sorts of people.
Not just mages.
[STARK]
Yeah, that's a good point.
This city is enormous.
Let's see what else
there is to see.
-[WOMAN] It's beautiful!
-[MAN] Very.
We'd like to buy
this one, ma'am.
Yes, of course! Sure thing.
[indistinct chatter]
You've gotta be hungry
by now, right?
The snacks
at the stalls up ahead
smell delicious.
-[MALE SHOPKEEP] Enjoy!
-Whoa, these look amazing!
-Let's go find a table.
-Sure.
[Fern grunts]
Got you!
Are you okay?
[exclaims softly] I'm sorry.
[STARK] Hmm...
Those shoes
look hard to walk in.
One slip and you're down.
♪
Yet another Mr. Himmel.
It's like he follows us.
I gotta say, he really nailed
the pose in this city.
I agree.
[STARK] According to Frieren,
there are over
100 different poses
floating around out there.
[FERN] Sounds like they went
a little overboard.
[STARK] Seriously.
An entire day,
and we're still talking about
Mistress Frieren.
[FERN] Anyway, this place
is nice and quiet.
And the view is very pretty.
[STARK] For sure.
Hey, Fern,
if you had a bad time today,
you can just say so.
[FERN] I wouldn't say "bad."
But I haven't seen you smile
a single time.
[FERN] I don't know.
I really did like
all the places we visited.
But for some reason...
they didn't feel like
places you'd choose.
And now our date has come
and gone.
I'm sorry, Fern.
I actually had Frieren pick out
all the places we stopped.
And why would you do that?
I wanted you to enjoy it
and I felt clueless on my own.
It's our first date.
It's special.
I understand.
I'm a little sad
our date didn't feel
how I thought it would.
But...
♪
I'm also happy.
You worked so hard.
Thank you
for putting in that effort.
Of course.
♪
This moment
is perfectly peaceful.
How funny. Look at that cloud.
[chuckles] It's one of the
pork buns we ate earlier.
I was thinking the same thing!
[both laugh]
I feel so calm.
When my parents passed,
I never imagined
I would experience peace
like this again.
Yeah, I get that.
It's all thanks
to Master Heiter.
I could say the same thing
about my master.
♪
[Stark groans softly]
[EISEN]
Picky eaters do not make
for strong warriors, young man.
I have a question.
[EISEN] What's that?
Why did you take in
somebody like me?
♪
[EISEN] Because it's what
Himmel the Hero would've done.
♪
You seem to be
in a good mood this evening.
For a good reason?
Not really.
♪
[HIMMEL]
The final stop on our list...
And no luck.
We've officially searched
every nook and cranny
that the shopkeeper gave us.
We're hopeless.
So why is it you smile?
[Himmel chuckles]
[HIMMEL] I suppose
I'm just in a good mood.
Because today was a good day.
How can you
call the day good
when we spent it all trolling
the streets for a lost cat?
Simple.
Because I spent it all trolling
the streets with you, Frieren.
It was fun.
Despite us never finding
the cat?
[Himmel gasps]
Even if things don't go
the way you'd hoped,
there's still joy to be found
on the journey.
Today brought much joy.
Certainly enough
to put a smile on my face.
[FRIEREN] Mm...
[HIMMEL] All right.
We don't want Heiter and Eisen
beating us to it.
-So let the journey continue.
-[cat meows]
[both gasp]
[gasping]
-[Himmel gasps]
-[FRIEREN] That must be our cat.
[HIMMEL] Perfect timing, kitty.
Let's catch it!
♪
You did your hair
all fancy again.
These are the braids
that I receive
when my stylist
is in a good mood.
I can't tell the difference.
[FRIEREN] It's woven
into their very essence.
[STARK] You people expect
too much outta me.
29 YEARS AFTER THE DEATH
OF HIMMEL THE HERO,
IN THE NACHRICHT REGION,
LOCATED IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
It's gotten a little chillier,
hasn't it?
We are out
of the volcanic area now.
We should be able
to see it at any moment.
♪
[FERN] Is that the
Northern Plateau checkpoint?
Could they have made it
more intimidating?
Wait until you see the beasts
that lie on the other side.
♪
It'll be a long while
before we have access
to supplies again.
Let's get everything
we need while we can.
[BOTH] Hm.
♪
You could put a whole market
in that suitcase
and there'd still be room.
Nifty, eh?
[Stark gasps]
Uh?
[guard gasps softly]
Fern, the first-class mage.
Right this way, Miss.
You take care.
I forget she's a big deal.
When one reaches the pinnacle
of magical prowess,
you might want
to make a mental note.
[STARK] This is the big,
bad Northern Plateau?
From what I've heard,
I expected blood
and guts and chaos,
not a normal forest.
Are you being serious?
Just look around.
Look for what?
[FRIEREN] We're surrounded.
[growling]
[Stark gasps]
Stay on your toes.
This is merely the beginning.
-[growling]
-[Stark grunting]
[growling]
♪
[Stark sighs, groans]
[FRIEREN] It's a village.
I thought I was gonna die
out there. [coughs]
Three days and nights of blood
and guts and chaos.
I do hope we can rest here.
[MAN] Fine with us.
There's an extra cabin
no one's using.
Make yourselves at home.
-[exclaims]
-Thank you, sir.
Forgive me.
I do not wish
to trouble you, but...
A monster took over
the road north.
We're used
to dealing with beasts,
but this one's
a different story.
[MAN] The local knights
are powerless against it.
Traveling merchants can
no longer pass this way.
And as you can see,
adventurers rarely
visit this land.
In exchange for the cabin,
will you three please
slay the monster?
Sure. We're going north anyway.
We'll slay it
on our way out of town.
-Is that all right?
-[FERN] Yes.
I guess we can.
But won't another take
its place?
The checkpoint
is only three days away
from your village.
You know this place
is dangerous,
so why don't you move?
[man chuckles]
Dangerous it is,
even for our
northern sensibilities.
That said, this land is where
we were born and raised.
Look around.
Every pocket of this place
sings of the past.
And who could abandon
the home they love?
[Frieren chuckles softly]
[FRIEREN]
Shall we be off, then?
[goats bleating]
We wish you well.
-[horse neighing]
-[Stark gasps]
[monster grunting]
[growling]
A powerful beast, indeed.
Don't let your guard down.
-[monster growling]
-[Stark grunts]
[FERN] Too fast.
This monster isn't
like the others.
[FRIEREN] We've found ourselves
a formidable foe.
[monster growling]
[FRIEREN] The methods we've used
thus far aren't going to work.
Certainly seems that way.
Fine.
[Fern gasps]
-[monster growling]
-[Fern grunts]
[Stark gasps]
[monster growling]
[monster grunts]
Quite the eye on this one.
[growls]
Now, Stark,
while it's looking here.
Already on it!
[Stark grunts]
Sure, it's tough.
But I'm right there with it!
I won't let it beat me!
Frieren!
[Stark gasps softly]
[STARK] That thing was a force
to be reckoned with.
[FRIEREN] We've only just
entered the Northern Plateau.
That monster's strength
wasn't unique.
You should prepare for
similar battles down the line.
So there are creatures
like that all over the place?
This will be tricky.
I don't know, Frieren.
[FRIEREN] Mm?
The price was steep
to travel by sea,
but compared to this,
the hit to our purses
would've been worth it.
[Frieren chuckles softly]
[EISEN] I didn't expect to find
such a powerful monster here.
I was certain
we were going to die.
We should've sailed
past this region
if the road ahead is going
to remain as dangerous.
It will be dangerous.
That's why I chose it.
Many people live here,
you know.
The reason
that I became a hero
was because I wanted
to protect my homeland.
And now I want to protect
other people's homes, too.
Listen, Stark,
dangerous as it is,
there are many who call
this plateau their home.
[STARK] Huh?
♪
I didn't think
about it like that.
We'll fight for them.
Yes. That is our battle cry.
Right.
Thanks to Stark's reckless
abandon,
we scrounged out a victory.
If we want to succeed
going forward,
we'll have to focus
on increasing our teamwork.
[FERN] I agree.
Stop relaxing, teammate.
We still have much work to do.
It's bold of you to assume
I'm relaxing.
[BOTH] Hm?
As always, my legs gave out.
[Fern sighs] Pathetic.
It isn't like
I wanted them to!
That crazy spell
could've fried me!
I was nearly a pile of ash!
[Fern chuckles]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[FRIEREN] Don't come
crying to me later.
[STARK] Seriously,
what are we going to do?
[HIMMEL] Let go already!
[MINER] The president
told us about you.
[HEITER] But of course.
[NORM] " Logistics
in the Northern Plateau."